Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, ARRANGED BY SUBJECT, 1916-1982 (Boxes 45-56)
  - Slonim, Mark
    - "Strannyia oshybki g-na Slonima", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, April 21, 1953, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 42)
    - "Neudachnaia kniga o russkoi literature", review of Mark Slonim, Modern Russian Litrature: From Chekhov to the Present, Opyty, No. III, 1954, printed copy (Folder 43)
    - "Marc Slonim", obituary, Slavic Review, Dec. 1976, galley proof (Folder 44)
  - Sologub, Fedor
    - Translation (with Mary Kriger) of Fedor Sologub, typescript drafts, n.d.
      - The Petty Demon (Folder 45)
        - Author's Preface (Folder 46)
        - Chap. I-II
        - IX, XIX, XXI (Folder 47)
      - Children of the Earth, typescript draft, n.d.
        - "Beauty" (Folder 48)
        - "Consolation" (Folder 49)
        - "The Feather Bed" (Folder 50)
        - "Light and Shadows" (Folder 51)
        - "The Prosperous Judas" (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - "The Sting of Death" (Folder 2)
        - "Unto the Earth Things Earthly" (Folder 3)
        - Correspondence re publication of stories, 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr
    - "G. Lukach o Solzhenitsyne", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - "O povesti A. Solzhenitsyna", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 12, 1963, printed copy (Folder 6)
    - "Koe-chto o novom romane Solzhenitsyna", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 12, 1971, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 7)
    - "Ob odnom istochnike avgusta chetyrnadtsatogo", typescript draft, Oct. 3, 1971 (Folder 8)
    - "Behind the Front Lines: On Some Neglected Chapters in August 1914", typescript copy, 1972-1973 (Folder 9)
    - "Before and After Solzhenitsyn", letter to the editor, New York Review of Books, Jan. 22, 1976 printed copy (Folder 10)
  - Sviatopolk-Mirsky, Prince Dimitrii
    - "Kn. D.P. Sviatopolk-Mirsky o P. B. Struve", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - "Kn. D. P. Sviatopolk-Mirsky o russkoi poezii v 1922 godu", typescript draft, n.d. Includes afterword by Gerald Smith, "Stat'ia 'O sovremennom sostoianii russkoi poezii' i put' D. P. Sviatopolka-Mirskogo", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - Tarsis, Valerii
    - Letters to the editor, typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Untitled writing, typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - Tolstoy, Aleksei. "Alexey Tolstoy", obituary, The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1946, printed copy (Folder 15)
  - Tolstoy, Lev
    - "Tolstoy in Soviet Criticism", The Russian Review, Vol. XIX, No. 2, April 1960, printed copy (Folder 16)
    - "O tolstovskoi konferentsii v Venetsii", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 16, 1960, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - Tsvetaeva, Marina
    - "Prazhskie otkliki na smert' Mariny Tsvetaevy", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 18)
    - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to the correspondence between Marina Tsvetaeva and Vera Bunina (Folder 19)
    - Review of Marina Tsvetaeva, Remeslo and Psikheia, Rul', June 24, 1923, printed copy (Folder 20)
    - Lebedinnyi stan (Neizdannye stikhi, 1917-1921)
      - Business correspondence. Includes correspondence with publisher and orders received, 1957-1958 (Folder 21)
      - Introduction and commentaries, n.d. (Folder 22)
      - Galley proof (?), n.d. (Folder 23)
    - "Ob odnoi oshibke Mariny Tsvetaevoi", Russkaia Mysl', Dec. 6, 1963, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 24)
    - "Marina Tsvetaeva o liudiakh, o knigakh, o sebe", Russkaia Mysl', Aug. 14-28, 1969, printed copy (Folder 25)
    - "Posleslovie k pis'mam Mariny Tsvetaevoi k A. Teskovoi", Russkaia Mysl', Sept. 4, 1969, printed copy (Folder 26)
    - "Eshche o dne ot"ezda Mariny Tsvetaevoi v S.S.S.R.", Russkaia Mysl', Sept. 6, 1969, printed copy (Folder 27)
    - "O vospominaniiakh E. M. Mindlina", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 26, 1970, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 28)
    - "Zabytoe-ili poluzabytoe-stikhotvorenie Mariny Tsvetaevoi", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Aug. 20, 1977, printed copy (Folder 29)
  - Turgenev, Aleksandr
    - "An Ambassador-At-Large of Russian Culture", review of A. A. Saburov, ed., Pis'ma Aleksandra Turgeneva k Bulgakovym, typescript copy, 1940 (Folder 30)
    - "A Russian Traveller in Scotland in 1828: Alexander Turgenev", Blackwood's Magazine, Nov. 1945, typescript copy and reprint (Folder 31)
    - "Aleksandr Turgenev, Ambassador of Russian Culture in Partibus Infidelium", Slavic Review, Sept. 1970, galley proof and reprint (Folder 32)
  - Turgenev, Ivan
    - Translation (with Mary Kriger) of Ivan Turgenev's "The Man in the Grey Spectacles", typescript, n.d. (Folder 33)
    - "Turgenev and We", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 34)
    - Review of Edgar H. Lehrman, Turgenev's Letters, Slavic Review, Sept. 1962, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 35)
  - Vishniak, Mark. "Pravda antibol'shevizma. K 80-letiiu M. V. Vishniaka", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 12, 1963, printed copy (Folder 36)
  - Voloshin, Maksimilian
    - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy v dvukh tomakh, B. A. Filippov, G. P. Struve and N. A. Struve, eds., YMCA Press, Paris, 1982-1984, typescript drafts with handwritten corrections
      - "Stikhi raznykh let", pp. 1-171 (Folder 37)
      - "Kniga tret'ia. Neopolimaia kupina. Stikhi o voine i revoliutsii", pp. 221-391 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - "Paralipomena", pp.392-404 (Folder 2)
      - "Sviatoi Serafim. Poema", pp. 405-439 (Folder 3)
      - "Poslaniia", pp. 440-445 (Folder 4)
      - "Stikhi i neokonchennye poemy o Rossii i revoliutsii", pp. 446-482 (Folder 5)
      - "Nadpisi na akvareliakh", pp. 483-519 (Folder 6)
      - "Proza", pp. 520-594 (Folder 7)
      - "Prilozhenie tret'e. Primecheniia", pp. 1-169 (Folder 8)
      - "Prilozhenie chetvertoe. Bibliografiia Maksimiliana Voloshina.", pp. 1-66. Also includes handwritten notes (Folder 9)
      - "Ispravleniia i dopolneniia v tekstakh stikhov" (Folder 10)
    - Maksimilian Voloshin, Stikhotvoreniia i Poemy, B. A. Filippov, G. P. Struve and N. A. Struve eds., typescript draft, 1978 (Folder 11)
  - Vorontsov, Count Simon
    - "An 18th Century Champion of Anglo-Russian Alliance. Count Simon Vorontsov: Man Who Challenged and Beat Pitt", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 12)
    - "An Anglo-Russian Medley: Woronzows, Pembrokes, Nicolays, and Others", California Slavic Studies, galley proof and offprint, 1970 (Folder 13)
    - "Un chapitre oublie des rapports Russo-Polonais", Revue d'Histoire Diplomatique, Jul.-Dec. 1947, printed copy. See also "Letters to the editor", 1945 (Folder 14)
  - Vozrozhdenie
    - "P. B. Struve i 'Vozrozhdenie'", letters to the editor of unidentified newspaper, July 13, 1955, printed copies (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - "Stranitsa iz istorii zarubezhnoi pechati. Nachalo gazety 'Vozrozhdenie'", Mosty, No. 3, 1959, printed copy (Folder 2)
  - Zamiatin, Evgenii (Folder 3)
    - Review of Evgenii Zamiatin, My, Chekhov Publishing Co., New York, typescript copy, n.d.
    - Untitled writing, introduction to new translation of Zamiatin's We, notes and typescript draft (Folder 4)
    - "'My' Zamiatina na amerikanskoi stsene", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Nov. 19, 1978, printed copy (Folder 5)
  - Zaitsev, Boris
    - "Boris K. Zaitsev, Oldest Russian Writer", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 6)
    - "O Tishine Borisa Zaitseva", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Feb. 6, 1949, printed copy (Folder 7)
    - "O B. K. Zaitseve", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 2, 1961 (Folder 8)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, ARRANGED CHRONOLOGICALLY, 1916-1982 (Boxes 56-69)
  - "America Through the Eyes of a Soviet Novelist, Peter Pavlenko's Happiness", typescript copy, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - "Byvshie", typescript note related to Soviet interest in Russian emigre literature, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - "Comparative Literature in the Soviet Union: Today and Yesterday", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "The Cultural Renascence", typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - "Custine's Book and Russia Past and Present, An Open Letter to General Walter Bedell Smith", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "Eshche o K. Simonove", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "Eshche o 'konditsiiakh' verkhovnikov", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Eshche ob 'Apollone'", letter to the editor, Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - "La France devant les ecrivains russes", Le Mois, printed copy, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - "'Iz glubiny', (De Profundis)", letter to the editor of The New York Review of Books, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - "John Paradise, a Friend of Dr. Johnson and a Pensioner of Catherine the Great", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - "K istorii russkoi zarubezhnoi literatury. Kak sostavlialas' antologiia 'Iakor'", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - "K istorii russkoi zarubezhnoi literatury. Melochi iz kopilki moei pamiati. L. I. Strakhovskii--L. Chatskii", typescript draft (Folder 21)
  - "K sporu o 'Slove o polku igoreve'", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - "K stat'iam prof. M. Iu. Sheftelia", letter to the editor of Russkaia Mysl', typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - "Koe-chto o Pasternake i Rilke", typescript draft (Folder 24)
  - "Koe chto ob Isae Lezhneve i ego zhurnale", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 25)
  - Letters to the editor. Miscellaneous short or untitled handwritten and typescript drafts, n.d. (Folder 26)
  - "Listening to Khrushchev", typescript draft n.d. (Folder 27)
  - "Literatur in Sowjetrussland", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - "Literature of the Russian Emigration", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 29)
  - "Lobster Salad", holograph, n.d. (Folder 30)
  - "Moskovskoe radio ob ubiistve tsarskoi sem'i", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 31)
  - "My Personal Experience of 'Cultural Coexistence', typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 32)
  - "Nam pishut iz Munchena", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 33)
  - "O chistote iazyka i o ego vykholashchivanii", letter to the editor, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 34)
  - "O Konrade Adenauere", letter to the editor, Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 35)
  - "O Tvardovskom i Solzhenitsyne", letter to the editor of Tygodniu polskim, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 36)
  - "O slove utlyi", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 37)
  - "Ob odnom berlinskom literaturnom kruzhke", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Obituary of Mikhail Karpovich, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 39)
  - Obituary of Oleg Maslenikov, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 40)
  - "Otvet g-zhe Zhernakovoi-Nikolaevoi", letter to the editor, Novoye Russkoye Slovo, n.d., typescript draft (Folder 41)
  - "Otvet V. Rudinskomu", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, n.d. (Folder 42)
  - "P. B. Struve v 1918-1919", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 43)
  - "Polska a Rosja", letter to the editor of Wiadomosci Polskich, typescript draft (Folder 44)
  - "Pros'ba ispravit' oshybku", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - "The Puzzling Policy of Socialist Realism", typescript of lecture (?), n.d. (Folder 46)
  - "Recent Developments in Soviet Literature", typescript draft of lecture, n.d. (Folder 47)
  - "Recent Russian Studies On Other Slavic Literatures", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 48)
  - "Russia and Poland: An Historical Parallel", letter to the editor of Time and Tide, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 49)
  - "Russia As Seen Through Russian Newspapers and Publications", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 50)
  - "Russia, Poland and the West", letter to the editor of unidentified newspaper, typescript, n.d. (Folder 51)
  - "Soviet Literature in Perspective, Some Unorthodox Reflections", typescript, n.d. (Folder 52)
  - "Soviet Literature Since Stalin's Death", typescript of lecture, n.d. (Folder 53)
  - "The Study of Soviet Literature Here and There, Some Comments and Reflections", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 54)
  - Translation into Russian of Michael Arlen, "Kuda golubi otpravliaiutsia umirat'", holograph, n.d. (Folder 55)
  - Translation (with Mary Kriger) of Olga Forsh, "The Swan Neoptolemus", typescript, n.d. (Folder 56)
  - Translation (with Mary Kriger) of Alexander Green, "The Watercolor", typescript, n.d. (Folder 57)
  - Translation (with Mary Kriger) of N. Teffi, "Irochka", typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "Tri dokumenta iz arkhiva P. B. Struve", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Untitled creative writing, typescript, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to Anti-Westernism in Soviet literature, typescript copy (Folder 4)
  - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to the poetry of Nikolai Gumilev, Nikolai Morshen and Tatiana Gnedich, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to Russian literature in exile, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Untitled writing, n.d. Relates to Soviet reaction to Struve's assertion of anti-westernism in Soviet literature, holograph, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "U.S.S.R. in August 1939-Fact and Fiction, A Prophecy That Went Wrong", typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - "Vdokhnovenie i remeslo v tvorchestve", holograph, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - "The Writers", lecture delivered at unidentified conference, typescript text, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - "Krylatoe serdtse. Stikhi, 1915-1919", notebook of miscellaneous poetry, holograph (Folder 11)
  - Poetry, handwritten and typescript copies, 1915-1916 (Folder 12)
  - "Tramvai B", Svetlyi luch, typescript copy, 1915 (Folder 13)
  - "Stikhotvorenie", Russkaia Mysl', 1918, printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Iz stikhov Gleba Struve", notebook of holograph and typescript poetry, 1918-1940's (Folder 15)
  - "Stikhi", notebook of miscellaneous holograph and typescript poetry, 1918-1932 (Folder 16)
  - "Bolshevism As I Saw It", The Oxford Outlook, I, No. 2, June 1919, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "Russia: A Problem", The Oxford Outlook, II, No. 7, May 1920, printed copy (Folder 18)
  - Poetry, clippings from newspapers, 1915-1925 (Folder 19)
  - Poetry, holograph and typescript, 1921-1970 (Folder 20-21)
  - "Otryvok", Russkaia Mysl', March 1922, printed copy (Folder 22)
  - Review of B. Eikhenbaum, Melodika russkago liricheskago stikha, Russkaia Mysl', 1923, printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Russia and U.S.S.R.", article submitted to The New York Herald, July, 1924, typescript draft (Folder 24)
  - "Beseda s akad. P. G. Vinogradovym", Vozrozhdenie, 1925(?), printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Pravitel'stvennyi krizis vo Frantsii. Kakoi vozmozhen ishod?", Vozrozhdenie, Nov. 24, 1925, printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Zarubezhnyi s'ezd. Beseda s Riabushinskim", Vozrozhdenie, Nov. 28, 1925, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Zarubezhnyi s'ezd. Beseda s A. I. Guchkovym", Vozrozhdenie, Nov. 29, 1925, printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "Sovetskaia Rossiia ne iz 'avtokara'", Vozrozhdenie, Nov. 30, 1925, printed copy (Folder 29)
  - Notebook of clippings, miscellaneous printed articles, 1926-1931 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - "Poet s bol'shoi dorogi", Vozrozhdenie, 1926, printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "V bol'shevitskoi tiurme", Vozrozhdenie, 1926, printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Sekret g-zhi de Kaiafe", Vozrozhdenie, Dec. 2, 1926, printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "K. Chapek o Masarike i Beneshe", Rossiia, 1927(?), printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Mezhdu romantizmom i simvolizmom", Rossiia, No. 7, 1927, printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Vospominaniia frantsuza o Tukhachevskom", Rossiia, 1927, printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Zhenevskii i parizhskii kongressy. Beseda s prof. M. A. Kurchinskim", Rossiia, 1927, printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Kitaiskaia nerazberikha", typescript draft, May 1927 (Folder 9)
  - "Diplomat-predatel'. V. L. Burtsev o Rakovskom", Rossiia, Sept. 10, 1927, printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "'Sovremennye Zapiski'", Rossiia, Sept. 10, 1927. printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Taina Moissi--Gamlet v Parizhe", Rossiia, Oct. 22, 1927, printed copy (Folder 12)
  - "Glavnoe litso 'Tresta'. Kto takoi Iakushev-Fedorov? Beseda", Rossiia, Oct. 29, 1927, printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Poet i avantiurist. Sud'ba Artura Rembo", Rossiia, Oct. 29, 1927, printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "G.P.U. v Estonii", Rossiia, Nov. 12, 1927, printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Novyi sbornik stikhov. Andrei Blokh, Stikhotvoreniia", Rossiia, Nov. 26, 1927 (Folder 16)
  - "Zhizn' Bodlera", Rossiia, Dec. 17, 1927, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "Inostrantsy o polozhenii bol'shevikov", Rossiia, Dec. 24, 1927, printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Knizhnye auktsiony v Parizhe", Rossiia, Dec. 31, 1927, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Novyi razskaz ob otrechenii Gosudaria", Rossiia, Dec. 31, 1927, printed copy (Folder 20)
  - Book reviews, 1928, printed copies (Folder 21)
  - "Anglichanin o staroi i novoi Rossii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, No. 12, 1929, printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Desiatiletie bol'shevitskago vladychestva", Rossiia i Slavianstva, 1928, printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Dva zhurnala", Rossiia, 1928, printed copy (Folder 24)
  - Fragment of poem, title missing, Rul', 1928(?), printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Iugoslaviia na ispytanii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, No. 3, 1928, printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Kak akademik Delil uezzhal v Rossiiu", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1930, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "Marshal Pilsudskii v izobrazhenii Anri Bero", Rossiia, 1928, printed copy (Folder 28)
  - "Sud'ba Zarubezhoi Tserkvi", Rossiia, Sept. 12, 1927, printed copy (Folder 29)
  - "Bezhenskie razskazy", review of Boris Lazarevskii, Golos rodiny. Novye razskazy, Rossiia, Jan. 14, 1928, printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Tomas Khardi", Feb. 8, 1928, printed copy (Folder 31)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh", review of Nikolai Turoverov, Put', Rossiia, April 14, 1928, printed copy (Folder 32)
  - "Vnepartiinyi osvedomitel'nyi tsentr. Beseda s E. V. Sablinym", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Sept. 17, 1928, printed copy (Folder 33)
  - "Datchanin, pochuvstvovavshyi Rossiiu", Russkaia Mysl', Dec. 22, 1928, printed copy (Folder 34)
  - Book reviews, 1929, printed copies (Folder 35)
  - "Bol'shevitskii perevorot po dokumentam", review of Serge Oldenbourg, Le coup d'Etat bolcheviste. 20 octobre--3 decembre 1917, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929, printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "Mitskevich vo frantsii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929, printed copy (Folder 37)
  - "Piatidesiatiletie prof. R. V. Seton-Watsona", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929, printed copy (Folder 38)
  - "Professor Nevil Forbes", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929, printed copy (Folder 39)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, 1929, printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Franko-russkii miting protesta protiv krasnago terrora", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Jan. 1, 1929, printed copy (Folder 41)
  - "Roman o Griboedove", review of Iurii Tynianov, Smert' Vazir-Mukhtara, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Feb. 9, 1929, printed copy (Folder 42)
  - "Novaia kniga po istorii russkoi literatury", review of Nicolas von Arseniew, Die russische Literatur der Neuzeit und Gegenwart, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, March 30, 1929, printed copy. See scrapbook, 1926-1932 (Folder 43)
  - "Panorama sovremennoi russkoi literatury", review of Vladimir Posner, Panorama de la litterature russe contemporaine, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, April 6, 1929, printed copy (Folder 44)
  - "Literatura v 'Sovremennykh Zapiskakh'", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, April 20, 1929, printed copy (Folder 45)
  - "'Muzhitskaia drama'", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, April 20, 1929, printed copy (Folder 46)
  - "Pol'skii kritik o Mitskeviche", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, May 25, 1929, printed copy (Folder 47)
  - "Iz memuarov Brusilova", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, June 6, 1929, printed matter (Folder 48)
  - "'Olimpiiskii Lavr' K. Vezhynskogo", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, June 19, 1929, printed copy (Folder 49)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh. Parizhskie i prazhskie 'molodye'", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, June 22, 1929, printed copy (Folder 50)
  - "Angliia cherez slavianskiia ochki", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, July 20, 1929, printed copy. See scrapbook, 1926-1932 (Folder 51)
  - "Piamiatnik bolgaro-russkoi druzhby", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 10, 1929, printed copy (Folder 52)
  - "Strannaia kniga", review of Jules Legras, La litterature en Russie, Aug. 11, 1929, printed copy (Folder 53)
  - "Gr. V. N. Kokovtsev o Ekaterinburgskoi tragedii", Oct. 19, 1929, printed copy (Folder 54)
  - "Noveishaia pol'skaia poeziia", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Nov. 9, 1929, printed copy (Folder 55)
  - "Dva svidetel'stva o russkom iazyke", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Nov. 16, 1929, printed copy (Folder 56)
  - "Russkaia nauka za rubezhom", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Nov. 23, 1929, printed copy (Folder 57)
  - "Mitropolit Evlogii o bol'shevitskikh goneniiakh na tserkov", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Jan. 4, 1930, printed copy (Folder 58)
  - "O Moskovskom Universitete i brat'iakh kn. Trubetskikh", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Feb. 5, 1930 (Folder 59)
  - "Dva romana o liubvi", review of E. Kel'chevskii, V lesu and Iurii Fel'zen, Obman, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, printed copy (Folder 60)
  - "Mladorossy za revoliutsionnuiu bor'bu i obshchii front", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, July 19, 1930 (Folder 61)
  - "O mladorossakh i 'nepredreshenstve'", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 2, 1930, printed copy (Folder 62)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh", review of Iurii Mandel'shtam, Ostrov, Viktor Tretiakov, Solntseroi and Tretii sbornik Soiuza molodykh pisatelei i poetov v Parizhe, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 2, 1930, printed copy (Folder 63)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh", review of Perekrestok, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Aug. 30, 1930, printed copy (Folder 64)
  - "Rasskazy Valentina Kataeva", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Sept. 27, 1930, printed copy (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - "Svoeobraznaia pisarevshchina. Eshche o 'Chislakh'", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Oct. 11, 1930, printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Edinenie na putiakh k natsional'noi revoliutsii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Dec. 6, 1930, printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Zametki o stikhakh", review of Vladimir Dikson, Stikhi i proza and Ant. Ladinskii, Chernoe i goluboe, Rossiia i Slavianstvo, March 28, 1931, printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Le fantastique chez Osbert Sitwell", Le Mois, April-May 1931, printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Na vechere 'Perekrestka'. Fel'zen, Berberova, Poplavskii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, Dec. 7, 1931, printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Frantsuz o Rossii v 1840 g.", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, June 11, 1932, printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "O molodykh poetakh. Dovid Knut, Ladinskii, Smolenskii", Rossiia i Slavianstvo, July 23, 1932, printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Translation of S. Chevyrev, "Une visite a Balzac en 1831", Revue de Litterature Comparee, April-June 1933, tearsheets (Folder 9)
  - Review of George Reavey and Marc Slonim, eds., Soviet Literature: An Anthology, Slavonic Review, Jan. 1934, galley proof and printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "A Soviet 'Production' Novel", review of Valentin Kataev, Forward ,Oh Time, The Observer, Feb. 4, 1934, printed copy (Folder 11)
  - Letters to the editor, 1935 (Folder 12)
  - Soviet Russian Literature, (1935 and 1944 British editions, 1946 French edition)
    - Correspondence
      - Editions du Chene, 1946-1951 (Folder 13)
      - Longman's Green and Co., Inc., 1948 (Folder 14)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1948 (Folder 15)
      - Routledge and Kegan Paul, 1933-1976 (Folder 16)
    - Reviews, notebook of clippings, 1935-1951 (Folder 17)
      - 1935 and 1944 British edition
      - 1946 French edition
      - 1951 American edition
  - "Literature in Soviet Russia", The Nineteenth Century and After, Feb. 1935, printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Knjizevnost u savremenoj rusiji", Srpski Knjizevni. Glasnik, Dec. 16, 1935, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - Review of Janko Lavrin, Aspects of Modernism, 1936, printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Russian Studies", with S. Yakobson, The Year's Work in Modern Language Studies, Cambridge, 1936, printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "What Is Soviet Russia After", article submitted for publication to Empire Service, typescript copy, 1940 (Folder 22)